Jacob Wieler

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Driven software engineer with 2 years of professional full-stack development experience using popular languages/frameworks like React.js, Node.js, PHP, and Python. I love to learn new things and thrive in fast paced environments. I am a team player and enjoy working with like-minded individuals.

CONTACT

📞 (289) 716-2746

iacobwieler21@gmail.com

118 Drone Cres. Guelph, ON N1K 0B9 linkedin.com/in/jacob-wieler-95299 519a/

EDUCATION

April 2022 **Software Engineering**

Bachelor of Computing in Software
Engineering with a Minor in
Mathematics
UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH
– Guelph, ON.

KEY SKILLS

- JavaScript (React.js, Node.js, express.js, jQuery), PHP, C, Python, HTML5, CSS3
- SQL, Git, Agile Methodologies, scrum methods, pair programming, code reviews
- AWS (Lambda, EventBridge, CodeDeploy, APIGateway, Cloudwatch, EC2, S3, Elasticache
- Communication, collaboration. dependability, adaptability, problem-solving, mentoring

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical Lead

Prompt Core - Guelph October 2023 – Present

- Write and maintain infrastructure via AWS and Azure cloud providers
- Create unique solutions to evolving problems regarding LLMs and Al services like ChatGPT, DALL-E, and Azure Promptflow
- Develop processes to allow users to programmatically interact with LLMs and evaluate results in an efficient manner using the OpenAI API
- Guide company's technical decisions regarding languages, frameworks, cloud services, and product features
- Manage VCS, API keys, RDBMS, and cloud infrastructure

Software Developer

Adknown - Guelph May 2022 – October 2023

- Developed user interfaces using React.js and the MUI framework to ensure excellent UX for 30+ users
- Integrated backend using PHP to interact with our SQL databases to ensure data integrity and efficiency
- Utilized AWS resources for deployment, CI/CD, REST-ful APIs, WebSockets, and logging/alerting
- Wrote and maintained backend processes using PHP to automate and optimize ad campaign operations for thousands of ad campaigns

Software Engineer Intern

Adknown - Guelph January 2021 - August 2021

- Wrote and maintained external-facing sites with thousands of visitors
- Transitioned company to using modern JS framework for front-end (from jQuery/vanilla JS to React.js)
- Improved and maintained legacy backend code to assist marketing professionals to upload and manage ad campaigns